Hey AIEDU team,
this is my submission here for the program I built just as a mock-up
of the potential what this portal could look like.
I really enjoy AIEDU type things.
My son, he's five years old, already using some AI learning resources.
He's doing math at five at a second grade level,
so this is something that I'm more than happy to help you guys build
and support. What you're looking at right now is just the curriculum studio that
I built up. Right, the current system kind of lives across these different marketing
sites, different PDFs and pages,
things like that. Obviously, you guys are looking to upgrade that.
I thought for the app I'd show would be a mock-up of what could
potentially be used. Obviously,
all of this information was inferred based on the web information and the job
posting. In reality, what I would do is interview stakeholders.
Ideally, we would actually interview actual educators across the board,
as well as, of course, your internal team on what's going to be most
used for them. This project here,
this specific front end that I built here,
would be designed for two users, right?
You would have the educators looking through, we'd have filters based on size,
based on their grade,
things like that. Then we'd have the back end for admins here,
where they could move different courses into published,
into review, things like that.
Analytics on what's being used and what the team is,
is putting out. If you guys have back-end systems like ClickUp or other things
like that, we could build PM-based things,
to actually process these, build out what that looks like,
I'm sure you guys have some things in place for that already.
In terms of my process, when you start stuff out you want to build
a PRD, so I went ahead and did so,
had AI bots crawl your current site,
then, downloaded some HAR files based on the network interactions,
then we, I had Claude mock up our PRD here,
just inferring based on what we could identify.
Built it out into Cursor, right?
Open questions for stakeholders, like what it was the current team using
like obviously if we were to go through this we would triage the current
system we would work with ask questions the whole goal
here is we got to gain insight before we start trying to take action,
and when it comes to what you guys are looking to do,
you're going to, I don't know if you're selling to admin or whether you're
selling to educators directly, but educators are going to
fall in a distribution, right? We have the diffusion of innovation Simon
Sinek likes to talk about, look the educators are going to fall of course
across this diagram somewhere, right?
These innovators, early adopters, they're going to love stuff like this.
They're going to jump on board, the early majority, even a large portion of
them, maybe in AI, but there's a growing late majority.
In laggards, when it comes to embracing AI tools and things
that, you know, connect to our children are going to be things that these
people are exceptionally sensitive towards.
And any type of friction in a system like this
is going to bounce those individuals out immediately.
It's going to cause friction for, for administration in the schools
that are looking to pull this in. And our goal is to talk
to these stakeholders, understand what their thought processes are,
and like the old sales adage, the best way to beat out objections
is to prevent them in the first place. So let's do that with insight,
with identifying what those concerns are upfront.
And then as we look to develop things,
let's answer those questions before they even become concerns.
yeah. So what would I change in here? Obviously there's success
metrics in the PRD. How long does it take an educator to find the
resources they want, right? We would need to have that process mapped out
here, gain metrics on it, when it's under production or an alpha
testing, right? These are things we'd want to take into consideration.
What products percentage of uses have complete metadata?
What's admin time to publish on the backend in terms of the production
team? things like that. And again, the biggest gap in this entire system here
is my discovery is just,
again, inference from the public site.
The real version is going to start with stakeholder interviews with your programs,
learning teams, real educators,
and I'd expect a lot of the assumptions I made here,
at least several of them, to break, and that's exactly what Discovery is for.
If this were real, right, we'd have educator accounts maybe via Google or Education
SSO. Standard alignment fields,
if you're current, if you're using Airtable,
things like that, we'd have CSV, Airtable import for your team's existing content.
and of course, FERPA and COPA reviews to ensure that everything's in alignment
there. right, this role isn't just shipping product,
right? It's leaving your team,
you know, as I exit the role, leaving your team the ability to do
this without me. And that's been my model for 13 years as an ops
leader at my current client. I rebuild operations Train
the team it runs day to day right that team is taking care of
95, 99% of operations with only sporadic
leadership escalation. same pattern here,
documentation, templates,
good system practices, your staff in the room,
right? While we build screen share,
whatever we need to do. and for myself, I'm self-taught,
right? AI literacy is how I built a career designing systems and software.
So your mission is my origin story.
That's why I made the time to just go ahead and build this for
you guys So everything I showed PRD build log what I do differently
It's at the process page here right here.
I'll upload the video. You might even be watching it on this process page
right here. Happy to walk through it live and,
hopefully we can work together. See ya.